The most shattering experience you'll ever live.
Johnny Got His Gun is a war, drama film directed by Dalton Trumbo.
A young American soldier, rendered in pseudocoma from an artillery
shell from WWI, recalls his life leading up to that point.
Joe Bonham, played by Timothy Bottoms.
Kareen, played by Kathy Fields.
Joe's Mother, played by Marsha Hunt.
Joe's Father, played by Jason Robards.
Christ, played by Donald Sutherland.
Mike Burkeman, played by Charles McGraw.
Johnny Got His Gun is a 1971 American independent anti-war
drama film written and directed by Dalton Trumbo.
Based on his own novel of the same name, it was
Trumbo's first and only directorial effort.
The film stars Timothy Bottoms, Kathy Fields, Marsha Hunt,
Jason Robards, Donald Sutherland, and Diane Varsi.
Although it was a minor success upon its initial release, the film
was largely forgotten by the mass audience soon after.
It received renewed attention in the late 1980s after clips from it were incorporated into the popular
music video for Metallica's single "One", and the film has subsequently become a cult film.
Eventually, Metallica bought the rights to the film in order to be able to
show the music video without having to keep paying royalties.
The film explores themes of blindness and impaired vision,
experiment, amputation, world war i, deaf-mute.
The tone is emotional.